Greater Boston Area, MA

🛘 508-948-8872 | 🗷 nguyenjason06@gmail.com | 🏕 dangitjason.github.io | 🖸 github.com/DangltJason | 🗖 jnguyen576

Summary_

Charismatic technical leader who loves empowering a team to turn ideas into a reality. Part-time nerd who uses coding as a tool to solve personal problems. Ready to utilize technical skills, academic background and leadership in a professional experience to contribute to a greater-cause.

Coursework: Data Structures, Discrete Math, Differential Equations, Multivariable Calculus, Intro to Algorithms, Principles of Software

Skills: (proficient) Python (familiar): C/C++, Java, Git (learning): JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Node.js, Express.js, React, MongoDB

Skills Cont.: Microsoft Office, Team Management, Communication, Leadership

Work Experience __

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Science Department

Trov. NY

UNDERGRADUATE COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Guided new computer science students to build and develop proper programming practices during lab periods.
- Directly influenced growth of 30+ students through tutoring with Python programming exercises.

Vake Inc., REIT Boston, MA

SALES DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Increased sales lead generation by 25% by using web-scraping tools to accelerate the lead generation process.
- Leveraged strong interpersonal skills to attract and initiate consumer interest in company product.

Projects

GroupMe Chat Bot

PYTHON, GOOGLE API Dec. 2019

- Developed a chat bot using Python to inform group members of upcoming events.
- · Retrieved, stored and pushed important dates through Google Calendar API.

FitMe Mobile Android App

JAVA, USER AUTHENTICATION, FIREBASE, ANDROID SDK

Oct. 2019

- Developed an Android application using Java that allows users to track and develop workout routines.
- Used Firebase to build a secure user login authentication and registration system.
- Incorporated real-time data storage to archive personal user workouts.

CEO Gary Vaynerchuck Instagram Data Analysis

PYTHON, NUMPY, PANDAS, EXCEL

May. 2019

- Scraped over 5k posts and 5M+ comments using web-scraping tools for data analysis.
- Wrote Python scripts to edit and manipulate data and collect multiple CSV files into a single dataset.
- Used NumPy, Pandas and Excel to analyze and process datasets to analyze IG marketing strategy.

SchoolVR - Business Model Competition

PROJECT MANAGEMENT Oct. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- · Worked to build a company that offers an online education platform for virtual reality education called SchoolVR
- Engaged in customer acquisition through direct contact of 10+ US universities. Pitched product to local entrepreneurs and professors.
- Sketched out general scope and goals. Communicated roles and expectations to team. Monitored progress and identified roadblocks.

Education _

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Troy, NY

COMPUTER SCIENCE MAJOR AND MATH MINOR, 3.47 GPA

Aug. 2018 - Present

• Dean's Honor List: Fall 18', Spring 19'